Samson Okunola, Frontend Developer

Nigeria | +2349023966260 | Portfolio: okunolasamson.vercel.app | Email: smsnmiceal@gmail.com

Summary

An experienced full-stack developer with a strong emphasis on the front end. I have a track record of creating intuitive and engaging user experiences while meeting business and user requirements. My problem-solving skills, dedication to meeting deadlines, and ability to work both independently and in a team set me apart.

Experience

Zummit Africa Remote, Nigeria

Lead Developer (FE)

- Implemented over 40% of core features and functionality of major apps like Zapi
- Contributed to boosting productivity and reduced average development time by 50% by introducing tools, procedures and processes that ensure faster and better development
- I led the development of the second version of Zapi to MVP

Kappari Enterprise

Frontend Developer

Remote, Nigeria

Apr 2022 - Present

- I took charge of the company codebase and refactored to React
- I delivered clients' websites and apps based on their specifications and requirements with over 80% client satisfaction at two-thirds of the expected time frame.
- Reduction of the timeframe from ideation to production by more than 30%

Federal Palace Hotel & Casino

Onsite, Nigeria

Frontend Developer

Jan 2018 - Dec 2019

- Demonstrated exceptional dedication and professionalism, leading to two promotions within a year.
- Independently managed multiple areas of the hotel, including the coffee shop, bar, restaurant, and banquet services, showcasing versatility and adaptability.
- Enhanced sales and customer retention through outstanding customer service, resulting in a loyal customer base and positive feedback.

Education

Yaba College of Education

National Diploma - Computer Science

Dec 2021 - Present

Technical Skills

Programming Languages

- JavaScript
- Typescript
- Pýthon,
- Solidity

Frameworks

- React
- Vue,
- Nextis
- Expressis
- Nestjs
- React-Native

Tools

- Git
- Webpack
- Rollup
- Redux
- Jest
- Vitest,
- Cypress

Softskills

- Leadership
- Problem-solving
- Innovation
- Excellent Communication
- Teamwork